《訴訟雙雄》前情提要
我認識的人中從來沒有
I don't know anyone that has ever made
異地戀最后有結果的
a long-distance relationship work.
我沒法忍受自己讓你陷入這種境地
But I can't stand that I put you in this position,
我能想到的唯一辦法就是
and the only way I can see out of this
你去斯坦福讀書
is for you to go to Stanford.
你朝我開火就好  坦納
Come after me, Tanner.
這才是你今天來這里的目的
That's what you're here for.
你是真的在乎她的
You actually care about her.
你覺得他在里面
You think he didn't say some things in there
沒說什么傷我的話嗎
that got to me too?
但我卻沒把它們當回事  因為如今
Well, I'm not bringing them up, because right now,
我們得團結作戰
we need to stick together.
團結作戰的意思是得相互坦誠
Sticking together means telling the truth.
我不能忍受他們不斷找你麻煩
I can't stand to see them come after you.
你認為我承受不了嗎
You think I can't take it!
你沒明白我的意思
Look, you're not listening to me, okay?
是我承受不了
I can't take it!
如果你只是想跟我一起工作
If all you want to do is work with me,
我可以在別的地方找工作
I can find a job somewhere else.
斯科特  我想要的不止這些
Scottie, that's not all I want.
那就說出來
Then say it.
我希望我的生命中有你
I want you in my life.
我不想讓她走
I don't want her to go,
但現在我也無能為力
and there's nothing I can do about it.
我比較完了
I finished my list.
結果呢
And?
你要留下來
You're staying?
有本事就攔住我
Just try and stop me.
這里有哈佛法學院歷屆學生的檔案
This place has every Harvard law student file ever.
不準碰這里的任何檔案
Do not touch any of the files in here.
邁克·羅斯  他不在這兒
Mike Ross? He's not here.
想什么呢
What are you thinking about?
你真美
You look beautiful.
謝謝
Thank you.
你想什么呢
What are you thinking?
你的家具都好老
That your furniture's really old.
你是想說"古經典"吧
I think the word you're looking for is "antiquey."
那根本不是個詞
That is not a word,
這個沙發是宜家1994年左右的產品
and this sofa is Ikea circa 1994.
好吧  知道了
Okay, I get it.
你這么早起床  就是為了狠狠地
So you get up early just so you can do a thorough critiquing
挖苦我的家具
of my furniture?
其實  我這么早起床  是為了考慮
Actually, I got up early, so I could figure out
這里有沒有哪樣家具我能接著用
if there's anything around here that I could stand living with.
你是說...要搬過來一起住嗎
As--I'm sorry--do you want to move in together?
如果你還邀請我的話
Yeah, I mean, if the offer still stands.
開玩笑嗎
Are you kidding me?
這么說你同意了嗎
So is that a yes?
這才是同意了
Oh, no, this is a yes.
我知道我們要帶上什么了
I figured out what we can bring.
-什么  -你
- What? - You.
這個熊貓
Panda, right here.
這是我最喜歡的藝術品
That's my favorite piece of art.
那根本不是藝術
That is not art.
是奶奶給我的
Grammy gave that to me.
我喜歡  熊貓可以有
Oh, I love it. Panda can come.
還有這把椅子
And the chair.
那是奶奶最喜歡的椅子
That was grammy's favorite chair.
這我...
I don't--I don't--
不不不  我告訴你瑞秋
No, no, no, no, no, I'm telling you, Rachel,
以前她每周日都坐在椅子里
she used to sit in that chair every Sunday
喝她的好時熱可可
and drink her hot cup of Hershey's cocoa
跟我講述她小時候
and tell me all about growing up
在費城壞街區的事
on the mean streets of Philadelphia.
撒謊的時候  別說得那么詳細
When you lie, try less details.
明白
Got it.
找我呢
Looking for me?
不是
No.
我要找的女人應該還在我床上呢
The woman I'm looking for is a lot more in my bed.
沒辦法  我的日程不等人啊
What can I say? My schedule stops for no man.
是啊  但我們還有沒做完的
Yes, but we've got a little unfinished...
事呢
business.
我覺得昨晚不差什么了
I wouldn't call last night "unfinished."
也不算是"公事"
And I wouldn't call it "business."
我指的是早餐
I was talking about breakfast.
哈維·斯佩克特還做早餐
Harvey Specter makes breakfast?
沒聽說過斯佩克特特色餐嗎
You never heard of the Specter special?
我好像剛剛嘗過了
I think I just had the Specter special.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
-斯佩克特特色餐是  -我猜猜
- The Specter special is - Let me guess.
兩個雞蛋  煎兩面
It's two eggs, over easy,
配菜是  "斯科特
with a side of "Scottie,
我希望我的生命中有你"
I want you in my life."
熏肉
Bacon.
我要重新考慮一下進入我生命中的事了
And now I'm reconsidering the "in my life" thing.
休想  我看到你的表情了  你是認真的
Oh, no, I saw your face. You had your serious face on.
斯科特  我希望我的生命中有你
"Scottie, I want you in my life.
Scottie... I want you in my life."
跟你說  不給你做熏肉了
You know what? You don't deserve my bacon.
無所謂  反正我得走了
Oh, that's fine, 'cause I have to go anyway.
你能去哪啊  你丟了工作
Where could you have to go? You're unemployed.
其實  昨晚有家一流的律所提出雇傭我
Well, actually a top-tier law firm offered me a job last night,
我覺得我應該去跟
and I thought it might be best
我沒在跟她上床的那位合伙人
if I negotiate the terms of my agreement
討論合約的條款
with the partner I'm not sleeping with.
這個計劃有個小問題
There's a slight problem with that plan.
你沒跟我商量就提出要給她一份工作
You offered her a job before talking to me?
我沒有  我只是問她是不是想要工作
I didn't offer her a job. I asked her if she wanted one.
我不想浪費你的時間  而且
I didn't want to waste your time, and for the record,
我們有她加入肯定是好事
we'd be lucky to have her.
這我知道
I know that.
但我的問題不是為什么想要她加入
But my question isn't why I should want her here,
而是你為什么想要她加入
it's why you would want her here.
她是我認識的最好的律師  僅次于我
She's the best lawyer I know, after me.
還有你
And you.
你在跟她上床嗎
Are you sleeping with her?
什么
Excuse me?
你跟她有段歷史
You have history with this woman,
我只是想知道
So I just want to know
你這么做是出于同情
are you doing this because you feel sorry for her
還是想回報她
or because you want to pay her back
還是因為你愛她
or because you love her or what?
-不關你的事  -就關我的事
- It's none of your business. - It is my business.
這就是我的公司
It is literally my business.
我想跟她好好發展
I want a relationship with her.
我替你高興
Well, I'm happy for you.
-希望你們能成功  -謝謝
- I hope you two make a run at it. - Thanks.
我就當做你是真心的
I'll pretend you meant that.
你的記錄不怎么樣
Your track record isn't great.
你兩年換了三個合伙人
You've had three name partners in two years.
有承諾問題的是你吧
Let's talk about your commitment issues.
但我沒讓你給我承諾問題一間拐角辦公室
I'm not asking you to give my commitment issues a corner office.
你不用給她拐角辦公室
You don't need to give her a corner office.
正常的辦公室就行
Any regular office will do.
哈維  我懂
Harvey, I get it.
她對你  對這家律師  都不可多得
She's a catch, for you and for this firm.
但如果你們分手了會怎么樣
But what happens when you two break up?
誰說我們會分手
Who says we're gonna break up?
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：草草   圈圈   feilixiaozi   王大可   Reginamoon
翻譯：某豚   小小   七個柚子醬   貓咪賜我速死   親愛的小飯
校對：油炸電風扇     時間軸：JimmyBeck   小式   珞珞
后期：冰冰愛尖尖     總監：swears
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
訴 訟 雙 雄
第三季   第十一集
福爾曼和心臟醫療的案子  我想要
Foreman versus Heart Med-- I want it.
你不是該說"早啊  哈維"
"Good morning, Harvey.
-"有什么吩咐嗎"  -我是認真的
- What can I do for you today?" - I'm serious.
他們想促成和解
They're pushing for a settlement
因為他們知道我們的客戶付得起和解金
because they know our client can afford it.
我知道
I know they are.
你文件都沒看過怎么知道
You haven't even looked at the file.
律所大門上掛著我的名字呢
My name is on the door.
你以為我不知道我們有什么案子嗎
You think I don't know our cases?
那為什么要同意和解
So why are we settling?
因為雖然這個案子我們有利可圖
Because regardless of the merits of this case,
但是不值得我們去花那個時間
it's not worth our time.
哈維  聽我說
Harvey, listen--
心臟醫藥自己的律師來促成和解
Heart Med's in-house lawyer negotiated this
是因為公關做不好的代價不止是付和解金
because the bad PR costs them more than the settlement.
我們要讓對方撤訴才真的物有所值
We'd have to get the thing dismissed to make it worth it,
但是這是不可能的
and that's not gonna happen.
對方律師是尼克·里納爾迪
The lawyer is Nick Rinaldi.
-尼克·里納爾迪是誰  -你不記得了嗎
- Who the hell is Nick Rinaldi? - You don't remember?
我當時還是個11歲的小孩子  孤獨無助
I was 11 years old, a little boy, powerless.
眼睜睜地看著他把我父母的生命定為幾個美元
I watched him boil my parents' lives down to a few dollars.
好
Yes.
我不會再讓那個混蛋從我們這里拿走一分錢了
I'm not gonna let that piece of shit get a penny from us.
我答應你了
I said yes.
謝謝  哈維
Thanks, Harvey.
你想謝我的話
You want to thank me,
就去好好給那個家伙點顏色看看吧
why don't you go beat the shit out of this guy?
星期一  下午兩點二十分
Monday, 2:20 p.m.
這件事我一直想不明白
This conundrum is burning a hole in my brain.
再想想
Think.
邏輯地去想
Logically.
希拉做事專業  一絲不茍
I mean, Sheila is professional and meticulous
而且床技驚人
and wonderfully anal,
如果她說她的秘密小屋里
and if she says that nothing gets misplaced
一切準確的話  那我相信她
in her inner sanctum, then I believe her,
也就是說只能是國家安全行動了
which leaves the national security option.
難道邁克·羅斯是中情局的
Is Mike Ross CIA?
別逗了
Please.
那還不如說埃斯特是克格勃更靠譜
There's a better chance that Esther's in the KGB.
我可以直接去問希拉
I mean, I can ask Sheila,
如果我不想好好對待自己的蛋蛋了的話...
if I'm no longer fond of my testicles, which--
等等  消失的蛋蛋  消失的文件
Wait a second, missing testicles, missing file.
如果本來就不存在就談不上消失了
It can't be missing if it doesn't exist.
蒼天吶
Holy shit.
要是邁克·羅斯根本沒念過哈佛呢
What if Mike Ross never went to Harvard at all?
要是他只上過一個三流法學院呢
What if he just went to some crappy third-tier law school,
比如福特漢姆或者亞利桑那州立法學院
like Fordham or Arizona State?
你好  老兄
"Yeah, hey, bro.
不  派對上見吧
"Yeah, no, I'll see you at the party.
我不去復習司法考試了
"I'm not going to study for the bar.
說得對  還是兄弟靠得住
"Damn straight, that's right, bros before hos.
誰說不是呢  行了  夠了
Oh, yeah, you know--" All right, that's enough.
他這是一顆老鼠屎壞了我們一鍋粥啊
He's been peeing directly into our pristine pool of eliteness.
他真是...  糟了  快沒電了
He's been--oh, shoot, it's blinking out.
諾瑪  我馬上就說完了
Norma, really quickly,
你一定要再堅持一會兒...
I need you to get a pack of rechargeable --
該死  沒電了
Shit, it's out.
那我只是在自言自語罷了
So I guess I'm just talking to myself.
哈維說服我了  我們談談吧
Harvey convinced me, so let's get to it.
-我想要安置費  -沒問題
- I want a relocation fee. - Done.
還要10%的簽約獎金
And a 10% increase on my signing bonus.
7%
7%.
你給了哈維10%啊
You gave Harvey 10%.
你覺得你跟哈維一樣值錢嗎
Do you think you're worth as much as Harvey?
我沒他那么討人厭
I'm less of a pain in the ass.
那就10%
10% it is.
沒人一開口就這么高價碼的
Now, no one ever opens with the big stuff,
所以你告訴我你真正的目的吧
so why don't you tell me what you're really after?
你明知故問
You know what I'm after.
這家律所的名字是皮爾遜-斯佩克特
The name of the firm is Pearson Specter.
雖然以前改過很多次  但是不會再改了
It's changed too many times, and it's not going to change again.
永遠都不會嗎
Never?
我從來不說永遠
I never say never.
-正合我意  -當然了
- That's all I'm looking for. - Of course.
畢竟誰也說不準幾年后會是什么樣子
After all, who knows where any of us will be in a few years?
你  我  哈維
You, me, Harvey.
我們剛才是不是轉移話題了
I think we just changed the subject.
確實如此
We did.
現在我就告訴你我真正的目的
Now it's time for me to tell you what I'm really after.
你想知道我對哈維有多忠心
You want to know how committed I am to Harvey.
我想知道你對我有多忠心
I want to know how committed you are to me.
-你有多認真  -認真什么
- How serious are you? - About what?
我
Me.
我們不是說過了嗎
We had this conversation.
我們開始說的時候
We had this conversation
我還不用花費五十萬美金呢
before it was going to cost me $500,000.
杰西卡讓你提前支付入股款嗎
Jessica's making you pay the buy-in up front?
-對  -該死
- Yep. - Shit.
那你怎么說的
What did you say?
我說我不想交
Well, I said I don't want to have to pay
哈維·斯佩克特女友附加稅
a Harvey-Specter-girlfriend tax.
這可不是稅
You're not exactly paying a tax.
你只是提前入股而已
You're just buying in early.
哈維  公司設有六個月試用期
Harvey, there's a reason that firms are designed to have
是有原因的
a six-month trial period.
是為了看你是否適合這個公司
Yeah, to see if it's going to work out.
-沒錯  -你認為不適合
- Exactly. - Which you don't think it will.
我的意思是我得知道
I'm saying that I need to know
"我希望我的生命中有你"到底意味著什么
what "I want you in my life" really means.
你心知肚明
You know what it means.
意味著我想跟你在一起
It means I want to have a relationship.
但我還沒準備好向你求婚
But it doesn't mean that I'm ready to give you a ring.
你以為我準備好跟你結婚了嗎
You think I'm ready for a ring from you?
那你都準備什么了
Then what are you ready for?
我準備好了要是不行的話
I'm ready for it not to cost me a $1/2 million
不用花我五十萬的方法
if it doesn't work out.
你是說要是不行  你就會離開嗎
So if it doesn't, are you saying you're going to leave?
你希望我留下嗎
Would you want me to stay?
我都想象不到你怎么能跟我分手
I don't even know what you're gonna do to break us up.
哈維  我是認真的  我...
Harvey, I'm not kidding. I'm...
我害怕
I'm scared.
芝加哥瑞生律師事務所
You know, I just got an offer
剛剛向我提出了邀請
from Latham & Watkins in Chicago,
我不想去  但...
And I don't want to take it, but...
我得知道你是認真的
I need to know that you're serious about this.
斯科特  我是認真的
Scottie, I am.
說得容易  又沒人讓你拿五十萬美元
Yeah, but nobody's asking you to put up $1/2 million.
或許我們可以做到
Maybe we can make it
讓你不用掏錢
so nobody's asking you to do that either.
里納爾迪
Rinaldi.
還記得我嗎
You remember me?
詹姆斯·羅斯和妮娜·羅斯
James and Nina Ross.
不錯
That's good.
你終于知道我父母的名字了
Finally know my parents' names.
但你可能不知道  我是個律師了
What you maybe don't know is that I'm a lawyer,
在皮爾遜-斯佩克特工作
I work for Pearson Specter,
福爾曼案我們不會和解
and we're not going to be settling this Foreman suit.
我們已經談好了
We had an agreement.
或許吧  但是
Yeah, maybe, but instead,
我們要填這個了
we're gonna be filing this.
案子不可能被撤銷
There's no way you're getting this case dismissed.
我真希望相信那個關于改革重組的
You know, I actually wanted to believe that whole sob story
煽情故事  但是...
about being reformed, but--
我的客戶是個寡婦  不是醉酒的司機
my client is a widow, not a drunk driver.
所以你就不再嚇唬那個人
Oh, so you don't actually bully the little guy anymore,
打算利用他了
you just try and capitalize on him.
你到底知不知道案子的細節
Do you even know the details of this case,
還是因為我是對方的律師就咬著不放
or are you just coming after us because I'm on the other side?
不  我跟你糾纏
No, I'm coming after you
是因為你是個無能的事故賠償律師
because you're a worthless ambulance chaser,
我不會讓你拿走我客戶的一分錢
and I'm not gonna let you take my client's money.
這已經是第二次你對我
This is the second time you've come after me
搞突然襲擊了
from out of the blue.
上次我道過歉了
I apologized to you once.
這次我不會再道歉了
I will not apologize to you again.
你不用道歉
You don't have to.
不會有庭審的
And we're not going to court,
因為我會證明你是個滿嘴胡話的瘋子
because I'm gonna prove you're full of shit.
準備好取證了嗎
You ready for the deposition?
當然準備好了
Yeah, of course I'm ready.
-你褲鏈沒拉  -瞎說
- Your fly is unzipped. - No, it's not.
你都沒猶豫
Didn't even flinch.
說明你準備好了
That means you're ready.
那你還跟著我干什么
Then why are you still walking with me?
因為我也參加取證
Cause I'm coming to your deposition.
什么  等等  等一下
What? Whoa, whoa, hey, hey.
你說過這案子歸我負責
You said that I could take this case.
你說我會打得對方落花流水
You told me I could kick this guy's ass.
這是我的取證  不是你的
It's my deposition, not yours.
-我知道  -你知道
- I know. - you know?
-那你為什么看著我  -我沒看著你
- Why are you babysitting me? - I'm not babysitting you.
我想親眼看你手刃他
I want to watch you kill this guy.
所以才準備了零食
That's why I brought snacks.
你可不能把花生帶進取證現場
You can't bring peanuts into my deposition.
-為什么  -太不專業了
- Why? - It's unprofessional.
你那領帶也是  可我都沒計較
So is that tie, but I've made my peace with it.
我才不管你
Look, I don't give a shit
計較什么
whether you made your peace with it or not.
你想參加取證
You want in my room?
就不許帶花生
You're not bringing peanuts.
真是準備好了啊
You really are ready.
接著
Here.
什么東西
What's this?
邁克·羅斯被錄取那天哈維的面試名單
Harvey's interviews the day Mike Ross was hired.
但邁克·羅斯不在上面
But Mike Ross isn't on it.
你在哪拿到的
Where'd you get this?
那不重要  反正已經拿到了
Doesn't matter where I got it. The fact is I did.
你是想問為什么邁克·羅斯不在上面嗎
Are you asking me why Mike Ross isn't on it?
是的  唐娜  我就想問這個
Yeah, Donna, that's precisely what I'm asking.
哈維是怎么找到他的
How exactly did Harvey find him?
不是我們找到了他  是他找到了我們
We didn't find him, he found us.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
邁克沒有及時報名面試
Mike hadn't signed up for the interview on time,
所以他假裝成名單上的律師
so he pretended to be one of the other associates on the list.
他說服了我
He talked his way past me
還給哈維留下深刻印象
and impressed the shit out of Harvey,
哈維就想招一個
whose main requirement was somebody who had the balls
有膽量這么做的人
to do something like that in the first place.
好吧
Okay.
如果他有膽量做些
What if he had the balls to do something
比這嚴重的多的事呢
a lot bigger than that?
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
我認為邁克·羅斯上的是一所很差的法學院
I think Mike Ross went to a subpar law school
而且一直在用謊言掩蓋這個事實
and has been lying about it the whole time.
路易  聽聽你自己說的話
Louis, listen to yourself.
你說的可是邁克
You're talking about Mike.
你簡直瘋了
You're insane.
我
I'm--
好吧  我曾和希拉去過哈佛檔案室
Okay, I was in the Harvard file room with Sheila.
別問我細節
Don't ask details.
我發現那里沒有邁克·羅斯的檔案
And I noticed Mike Ross' file was not there.
你還專門去找了他的檔案
You specifically looked for his file?
是的  我也找了哈維的
Yes, and I looked for Harvey's too,
他的就有
and his was there.
順便說一句  他過去看上去像個蠢貨
And by the way, he looked like a major douche.
所以你在數以萬計的檔案里面
So you looked at a grand total of two files
尋找兩個檔案
out of tens of thousands,
然后就得出了這個結論
and this is the conclusion you jump to?
你到底出了什么問題
What is wrong with you?
你不了解希拉
You don't know Sheila.
她就像個外科醫生  這些檔案就是病人
She's like a surgeon, and the files are her patients.
她不會犯錯誤
She doesn't make mistakes.
-那你跟她講過這件事嗎  -當然沒有
- You told her about this? - Hell no.
她讓我不要碰任何檔案
She told me not to touch any of those files,
如果被她發現  她會殺了我
and she'd kill me if she found out that I did.
我只是泛泛的問了一下
I just asked her about it generally.
她當然會說自己從來沒丟過檔案
Well, of course she's gonna say she never loses one,
但就我的個人經驗來說
but I can tell you from personal experience,
任何事情都有可能發生
anything can happen to a file.
-我不知道  -我知道
- I don't know.- Well, I do.
我了解邁克  我知道他的本事
I know Mike, and I know he's for real.
但如果你還是懷疑  有個很簡單的方法
But if you still doubt it, there's an easy answer.
給哈佛打電話要一份他的成績單復印件
Just call up Harvard and ask for a copy of his transcript.
如果這東西不存在呢
And what if it's not there?
那我會就像你道歉  叫你瘋子的事
Then I will apologize for calling you insane
并且親自幫助你把邁克·羅斯趕出大廈
and personally help you escort Mike Ross out of the building.
再見
Good-bye.
2002年  你因為一個舊款心臟支架
In 2002, you were sued for the malfunctioning
失效而被起訴
of an earlier model of the heart stent.
對嗎
Is that correct?
是的  并且我們承認了過失
Yes, and we admitted wrongdoing.
安裝在你病人體內的支架是一個
The stent that was installed in your patient was a new model
經過三年大量實驗研發出的新型號
developed through three years of extensive trials.
因此不在討論范圍內  而且實話實說
Making it outside the scope, and frankly, not a good argument
那也并不是一個建立模式的好論點
for establishing pattern.
他們發現了問題  并解決了它
They saw a problem, and they fixed it.
太糟了  我們應該起訴他們啊
How horrible, we should sue them.
我們現在并沒有在法庭上
We're not in court.
開庭陳述是要說給法官聽的
Opening statements are made before a judge,
還是你根本就沒上過庭
or have you never been in court before?
我就是想讓你先體會一下
I just wanted to give you a taste,
因為也許我們根本上不到法庭
seeing as we're never actually gonna get there.
這個案子不可能被駁回  孩子
A dismissal is never gonna happen, son.
我很抱歉  孩子
Sorry for your loss, son.
什么
What?
我是說不要期待這個案子被駁回
I'm saying, don't hope for a dismissal.
請對我們的客戶直接提出你的問題
Please direct your questions to our client.
我所說的不是問題  只是觀點
That wasn't a question. It was a comment.
確實有個問題  戴蒙德先生
Here's a question for you, Mr. Dimond.
這個案子對你來講到底意味著什么
What is this really worth to you?
你也許認為你能贏
You may think you have a defense.
但你的律師似乎認為你一定贏
Your lawyer certainly thinks you do.
但我只想跟你表明一下事實
But I just want to be clear about the facts.
這個案子對你來講到底意味著什么
What is this really worth to you?
毫無疑問  這是個可怕的意外
There's no question, this was a terrible accident.
但跟你表明一下事實
But let's be clear about the facts.
他的血液酒精含量是個問題
His blood alcohol level is an issue here.
如果你堅持上庭
If you pursue this in court,
你可能什么都得不到
there's no guarantee you'll receive anything.
為孩子想想
Think about the boy.
想想他需要什么
Think about what he needs.
有總比沒有好
Something is better than nothing.
別愣神了  羅斯先生
Stop stalling, Mr. Ross.
-我  -他不是在愣神
- Um, I-- - He's not stalling.
并且我們沒有義務
And we're under no obligation
公開之前那個型號的實驗信息
to disclose trials from an earlier model.
這不在討論范圍內
It's beyond the scope.
我們的專家會想辦法把它列入到范圍內的
Our expert will place that study within the scope.
如果我們不上庭
If there isn't a trial,
你的專家根本就沒有范圍可以列入
your expert won't have any scope to place it in.
鑒于你堅持要提一些
And since you insist on asking questions
我們沒有義務回答的問題
we're under no obligation to answer,
此次取證結束了
this deposition is over.
剛才出了什么事
What the hell happened in there?
你說你只是看看  不會搶我的案子
You said you wanted to watch, not hijack my case.
你還說你會好好教訓他呢
You said you were going to kick his ass,
而不是夢游仙境
not drift into never-never land.
-我在處理了  -處理
- I'm handling it. - Handling it?
你回答那個問題的間隙
I could've eaten that whole bag of peanuts
我都能吃完整包花生了
in the pause you took to answer that question.
你出局了  而我把你保了下來
You got thrown, and I bailed you out.
哈維  這是我的案子
Harvey, this is my case.
這不是你的案子  是客戶的案子
This is not your case. It's the client's case.
而且經歷了剛才那一幕
And after what happened in there,
他們的處境比剛開始時更糟了
they're in a worse position than when we started.
我知道剛才被修理了  但我能挽回局面
Look, I know I got thrown, but I can still recover.
也許吧
Maybe,
但是他們一個半小時之內就會打電話過來
but they're gonna call in a half an hour
想要和解了
wanting to take the deal,
到那時  我會幫你拖一天
and when they do, I'm gonna buy you one day,
然后我就結了這個案子
and then I'm pulling the plug.
有空嗎
Hey, do you have a minute?
-我這會兒有點忙  -我們有麻煩了
- I'm a little busy right now. - We have a problem.
斯科特不會惹麻煩的
Scottie's not going to be a problem.
我全面考慮過了
I thought it through--
路易可能發現邁克的事了
Louis might be onto Mike.
他在哈佛的檔案室里
He found out that Mike doesn't have a file
沒找到邁克的檔案
in the Harvard file room
還發現他不在你原先的面試名單上
and that he wasn't on your original interview list.
你和他說了什么
What did you tell him?
我把面試名單那個圓過去了
Well, I handled the list.
-那其他的呢  -我還能怎么說啊
- What about the other? - What could I tell him?
我告訴他假如他真這么好奇的話
I mean, I told him if he was so curious,
他可以索要一份邁克的成績單
he could order a copy of Mike's transcript.
那我們就沒什么麻煩了
Then we don't have a problem.
你不覺得我們該做點別的什么嗎
Well, don't you think maybe we should do something else?
不管做什么都只會讓他更加懷疑
Anything else is just going to make him more suspicious.
-你確定  -是的  我確定
- Are you sure? - Yeah, I'm sure.
好吧
Okay.
等等
Oh, wait a second.
你剛剛說路易去了哪里
Where did you say Louis was again?
他去了哈佛的檔案室
Oh, he was in the Harvard file room.
他怎么能進哈佛的檔案室
How was he in the Harvard file room?
他和希拉·賽斯有一腿
He has a relationship with Sheila Sazs.
什么
What?
是的  別擔心  沒事的
Yeah, never mind. We're good.
謝謝
Oh, thank you,
但是不好意思  我現在沒時間
But I'm sorry, I don't have time.
這是食物  這不會耽誤你什么的
It's food. It's not going to stop you.
反而能讓你堅持下去
It's going to keep you going.
是的  但我不需要食物
Yeah, I don't need food.
我需要的是找到一些能讓我帶去
I need to find something I can take
明天的撤訴聽證上的東西
to this dismissal hearing tomorrow.
邁克  這和解開出的條件挺不錯的
Mike, it was a pretty decent settlement.
接受這個和解真有這么糟糕嗎
Would it really be so bad to just take it?
我爸就是個什么事
My dad was one of those guys
都喜歡慶祝的人
who liked to celebrate everything--
半歲生日  或是我第一次
the half birthdays or first time
在棒球小聯盟里把某個人三振出局
I struck someone out at little league.
我最后一次見他們時
And the last time I saw them,
他們在過他們的第一次約會紀念日
they were celebrating the anniversary of their first date.
他們當時很興奮  全部盛裝打扮了
They were so excited, all dressed up,
而我當時卻很惱火
and I was annoyed,
因為我不想
because I didn't want to
去我奶奶家過夜
spend the night at my grandmother's house.
所以他們出發前
So before they left,
我爸上樓來和我道別
my dad came upstairs to say good-bye,
我對他說  慶祝第一次約會真是傻死了
and I told him that celebrating a first date was stupid.
然后他就這樣看著我  好像對我說
And he just looks at me like,
"邁克  你完全不了解
"Michael, you have no idea
第一次約會有多重要"
how important a first date can be."
他們的第一次約會一定很棒
Theirs must have been a great one.
不不不  完全是一場災難
No, no, no, it was a total disaster.
他把酒撒了她一身  還忘帶錢包了
He spilled wine all over her. He forgot his wallet.
然后  不知怎么的  這個女人
And then, for some reason, this woman, you know--
這個他認為是完美的女人
this woman who he knew was just perfect--
同意了第二次約會
agreed to a second date.
然后同意了第三次
And a third.
然后同意了之后的一切
And everything after that.
我真希望我見過他們
I wish I could have met them.
他試著和我擁抱告別
He tried to hug me good-bye...
但我沒有抱他
but I didn't hug him back.
我甚至都沒下樓和我媽說再見
I didn't even go downstairs to say good-bye to my mom.
然后他們就去了
And then they were gone.
第二天早晨  里納爾迪出現在我們家
And then the next morning, Rinaldi shows up at our house,
他提供給我奶奶
and he offers my grandmother
相當于一年租金那么多的錢
the equivalent of one year's rent.
雖然里納爾迪沒有殺害我的父母
Rinaldi didn't kill my parents,
但他確實試圖告訴我我父母的命值多少錢
but he did try to tell me what their lives were worth.
但很抱歉  我知道我父母的命
And I'm sorry, but I know that my mom and dad were worth...
比那個數字多得多
a lot more than that.
別管那些食物了
Forget the food.
分一半文件給我
Give me half the files.
找個對沖基金的人怎樣  他們錢多
What about a hedge fund guy? It's big money.
野心再大一點
Think bigger.
奧巴馬
Obama.
我才不要撈個總統
I'm not going to land the president
來做我的第一個客戶呢
as my first client.
好吧  假如你覺得自己不行的話
Fine, if you don't think you can.
你無法操縱我去把奧巴馬撈來做客戶的
You're not going to manipulate me into trying to land Obama.
最好找個這樣的
Well, it better be somebody like that,
不然杰西卡不會放棄提前入股款的
or Jessica won't give up on her early buy-in bullshit.
我要是給自己找個搞體育的人呢
What if I got myself a sports guy?
事實上你稱呼人家為"搞體育的"
The very fact that you call it "a sports guy"
就說明這行不通了
means it's a no.
哈維  我不懂體育
Harvey, just because I don't know sports
不代表我不懂你
doesn't mean I don't know you.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
假如我要改變杰西卡的想法
If I'm going to change Jessica's mind,
僅僅拉個客戶是不夠的
I can't just land someone,
我得拉到個你拉不到的人才行
I have to land someone you couldn't.
沒有我拉不到的人
There's no one I couldn't land.
你以為我不知道北京發生的事嗎
You think I don't know about Beijing?
那是他的一家之言
That's his word against mine.
我猜我們現在就能搞清楚
I guess we can clear that up right now,
因為你看看  剛剛走進來的是誰
because look who just walked in.
你早知道他今晚會來
You knew he was coming here tonight?
你以為我喜歡阿根廷食物嗎
You think I like Argentinean food?
我只是要你拖住他一會兒
I just need you to stop him for a second.
懂了
I get it.
你從《上班女郎》那兒得來的主意
You got the idea from Working Girl,
他們毀了婚禮  以得到特斯克電臺
when they crash the wedding to get to Trask radio.
哈維  我不是什么小女孩
Harvey, I'm not a 14-year-old girl.
不需要從電影里學什么主意
I don't get my ideas from movies.
邁克爾
Michael.
邁克爾·菲爾普斯
╰→
哈維
Harvey.
我不想跟你說話
I have no interest in talking to you.
╰→
你好  我是達娜·斯科特
Hi. Dana Scott.
我和哈維共事  我不怪你
I work with Harvey, and I don't blame you.
我也不會愿意讓他代表我
I wouldn't want him to represent me either.
但公司的律師不止他一個
But he's not the only lawyer there.
我來猜猜
Let me guess.
你已經調查過我的記錄了
You've done your research on my record,
現在是想給我留下好印象
and you're here to impress me.
別的律師都會這么做的
That's what every other lawyer would do.
-我就沒有  -哈維  閉嘴
- I didn't do that. - Harvey, shut up.
我才不管你能游多快呢
I don't give a shit about how fast you used to swim.
我只在乎我幫你賺錢的速度有多塊
I only care about how fast I can make you money.
能有多快
How fast is that?
不如先坐下來  我再告訴你
Why don't you sit down, and I'll tell you?
-行  -好
- All right. - Okay.
哈維  不介意吧
Harvey, you mind?
-其實我...  -好極了
- Actually, I-- - Great.
明天見
I'll see you tomorrow.
見到你很高興  伙計
Good to see you, buddy.
北京那邊到底怎么回事
So what really happened in Beijing?
先喝一杯再說
Let's get a drink first.
好主意
Sounds good.
醫生  這程序有多常規
Doctor, how routine is this procedure?
西德·福爾曼本來在大概一周后
Sid Foreman should have been dancing
就能在女兒婚禮上跳舞了
at his daughter's wedding a week later.
但他心力衰竭了
Instead, he went into heart failure.
隆巴德醫生  2006年12月7日
Dr. Lombard, on december 7, 2006,
是否有病人在常規血管成型手術中
did a patient die on your table
死在手術臺上
during a routine angioplasty?
反對  法官大人  問題相關嗎
Objection, your honor. Relevance?
判斷他作為鑒定人是否合格  法官大人
It speaks to his qualifications as an expert witness, Your Honor.
允許提問
I'll allow.
是  有名病人死了
Yes, a patient died.
是否有人以醫療失誤為由起訴你玩忽職守呢
And was a malpractice suit filed against you for physician error?
那個案件被封存了
That case was sealed.
我沒有問你是否被封存
I didn't ask you if it was sealed.
我問的是  是否提起了訴訟
I asked if it was filed.
是
It was.
-和解了嗎  -幾乎沒什么...
- And settled? - For almost nothing--
反對  法官大人
Objection, your honor.
要求撤消提問  案件已被封存
Move to strike. The case is sealed.
目擊者不能提供
The witness isn't allowed to testify
關于該和解的證詞
to the details of that settlement.
反對有效
Sustained.
你此后進行過醫療工作嗎
Have you practiced medicine since?
對  一直在進行
Yes, I've been practicing.
抱歉  我想問你是否實施過手術
I'm sorry, what I meant to say is have you performed surgery,
為這一技能你訓練了七年
The job you spent seven years training to do?
沒有
No.
怎么  信心不足嗎
What, loss of confidence?
還是他們不讓
They wouldn't let you?
反對  推測行為
Objection. Speculation.
我希望問題得到回答
I want an answer to my question.
我選擇做其他事
I chose to do other things.
其他沒有致死風險的事情嗎
Other things that don't involve the chance of you killing people?
-反對  -撤回
- Objection! - Withdrawn.
你收入的基本來源是什么
What's your primary source of income?
鑒定人
I work as an expert witness.
你現在以作證維生
so you testify now to make a living,
因為你認為自己做不好
because you don't trust yourself to do the job
本身受訓該做的工作嗎
that you were trained to do?
我可以證實這宗案件的事實
I can speak to the facts of this case--
對  你可以證實
Yes, you can speak to them,
但連你自己都明顯的不信任自己
but how are we supposed to trust your opinion about them
讓我們如何信任你
when you clearly don't trust yourself?
你質疑了我的專家
You raised some doubts about my expert.
那也不會讓這個案子撤銷的
That isn't gonna get this case dismissed.
可能不會  但如果這是你能找到最好的專家
Maybe not, but if that's the best expert you can come up with,
那你的客戶大概能看到這場審訊的結果
then your client just got a taste of how this trial is gonna go.
我的客戶不會撤訴的
My client is not gonna drop this case,
我也不會
and neither am I.
那你是逼我走這步棋了
Well, then you are forcing me to use this.
這是福爾曼先生在女兒婚禮上的照片
It's a picture of Mr. Foreman at his daughter's wedding.
這是福爾曼先生在女兒婚禮上
It's a picture of Mr. Foreman drinking alcohol
喝酒的照片
at his daughter's wedding.
那是祝酒  不過一小口
It's a toast. It was one sip.
他的支架失靈兩小時前的一小口
One sip two hours before his stent supposedly malfunctioned.
他術后嚴禁飲酒
Alcohol was strictly forbidden following his surgery,
所以他的死亡是自身的責任
which makes him liable for his own death.
這完全是扭曲事實
This is a total twisting of the facts.
你證明不了它引起了任何事
You can't prove this caused anything.
你也沒法證明這只是一小口
You can't prove it was only one sip,
其實也無所謂  因為一旦我上交了這張照片
and it doesn't matter, because I submit this,
那就是受害者本身的過失  你的案子就沒了
it's contributory negligence, and your case is gone.
你還說我是怪物嗎
And you say I'm a monster.
那是因為你把你的客戶
Being a monster would be putting your client
讓她親自出庭作證
on the stand and making her testify
她丈夫的死是咎由自取
that her husband's death was his own damn fault.
你好啊  唐娜
Hi, Donna.
你好  路易
Hi, Louis.
我是個有擔當的爺們
I'm nothing if not a big man,
出錯的時候我會低頭認錯
and I am not ashamed to admit when I am wrong.
你拿到邁克的成績單了
You got Mike's transcript.
今早剛送到
Arrived this morning.
快看啊  邁克·羅斯是哈佛畢業的呢
Imagine that, Mike Ross went to Harvard.
-真"不敢相信"啊  -你說得對
- What a shocker. - You were right.
從不該懷疑他
Never should have doubted it.
只是很難相信
You know, it's just hard to imagine a world
希拉竟然也會出錯
in which Sheila made a mistake, though.
起碼這事已經真相大白
Well, it's just good you can put this to bed
你可以消停了
once and for all.
還有個事兒
Yeah, see, that's the thing.
既然希拉這么看重自己的能力
If Sheila's competence is that important to her,
我應該告訴她  看她怎么辦
I need to tell her about this, so she can fix it.
對了  路易
You know what, Louis?
我剛想起來
It occurred to me after we talked
我是唯一有當天哈維面試過的
that I'm the only one who has the list of associates
助理候選人名單的人
that interviewed with Harvey that day.
不是啊
That can't be right,
我從總服務器上下載了一份名單
'Cause I got a copy off the general server.
你拿到名單是靠威脅本杰明
You got a copy by bullying Benjamin
從而非法侵入了我的私人硬盤
into accessing my private files off my hard drive.
-這不像我的作風啊  -路易
- That doesn't sound like me. - Louis.
好吧  是我干的  可是我真的很好奇嘛
Okay, I did it, but that was only 'cause I was concerned.
你好奇就可以隨意侵犯我的隱私嗎
So your concern gives you the right to invade my privacy?
我...啥  就一個文件而已
I...what? No, it was just a file.
好大的膽子
How dare you?
你一副相貌堂堂的樣子
You pretend to be this gallant man.
對天發誓絕不涉足我的私人空間
You make a big show of how you would never cross into my area
除非我允許
without my permission.
我就是相貌堂堂  也沒膽侵犯你
I am gallant, and I would never dare.
你是沒膽當著我的面這么做
You wouldn't dare, because you'd have to do it to my face.
可背后搗鬼的事你可一點都不在乎
But you have no problem breaking my trust behind my back,
我不光是生氣
and that not only pisses me off,
我甚至開始懷疑
but it makes me question...
我到底還要不要和你再說一句話
whether I want to have a relationship with you at all.
非常抱歉  唐娜
I'm so sorry, Donna.
行了  路易  別說了
No, Louis, you know what...
-唐娜  我都道歉了  -我沒法
- No, no, no, Donna, I'm sorry. - No, I can't.
-別別別  -我沒法...
- No, no, no, no. - I can't...I can't even...
-我錯了  我錯了  -先閉嘴
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry. - No, shh! Don't speak.
我都沒法看你
I cannot even look at you right now.
不過我還是費心提醒你一句
And I don't even know why I'm gonna tell you this,
連我都被你氣成這樣
but if you pissed me off that much,
如果希拉發現你辜負了她的信任
what do you think Sheila's gonna do
她會作何反應呢
when you tell her you violated her trust?
說的有理
You're right.
謝謝你  唐娜
Thank you, Donna,
憋了這么久才發作  以拯救我生命中
for putting your anger on hold long enough to help me salvage
唯一一段不是跟貓咪展開的戀情
the single most important non-feline relationship of my life.
-你又淘氣了  -希拉
- Someone's been a bad boy. - Sheila.
你以為我發現不了嗎
You thought I wouldn't find out?
我希望是
I hoped you wouldn't.
你想要人家的小內內
If you wanted a pair of my underwear,
就直說嘛
you should have just asked.
你說這個啊  希拉
Oh, that, Sheila.
你來這里干嘛啊
God, what are you doing here?
你不高興看到我嗎
Aren't you happy I'm here?
我當然高興
Of course, absolutely.
-你看起來沒那么高興  -我高興過頭了
- You don't seem happy. - I'm overjoyed.
我就是...很驚喜嘛
I'm just, you know...I'm just surprised.
可你緊張得渾身冒汗
But you're all nervous and sweaty.
你知道的  我每次看見你
Come on, you know my sweat ducts get excited
-就激動成這樣  -那好
- when they see you. - Good.
看來你要再過度激動一點了
Because your sweat ducts are going to be working overtime.
什么意思
What?
奇爾頓飯店  305房  今晚等你哦
The Chilton, room 305, tonight.
你不必為了放棄案子
You didn't have to come all the way over here
還特意跑一趟
just to drop the case.
我是來告誡你別做錯事的
I came here to tell you you're doing the wrong thing.
我用不著聽你的是非觀
I don't need a lecture from you on right and wrong.
你之前問  我如何面對自己
You once asked me how I live with myself.
這么多年以來  我曾有個機會
Well, somewhere along the way, I realized I had a choice
讓自己看起來不這么混蛋
not to be on the side that made me feel like shit.
-你現在就這個處境  -我可不是混蛋
- You're on that side now. - Yeah, I don't feel like shit.
因為你覺得你在自盡其責
That's because you're telling yourself you're doing your job.
但實際上  你只是在踐踏某人
And I'm telling you that you're bullying someone
而不是同情他
who deserves your sympathy.
你好意思提"踐踏"
You really want to play the bullying card?
我奶奶失去了唯一的兒子
My grandmother lost her only son.
她這么痛苦  你卻利用了她
You used her grief against her.
跟這個無關
This has nothing to do with that.
我理解  你把我看成個惡棍
Look, I know, you need me to be the villain...
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
你本來就是惡棍
You are the villain.
那么恭喜了  你現在跟我一樣了
Well, then congratulations, because you just became me.
你說什么呢
What are you talking about?
你父親身亡當晚喝了兩杯酒
Your father had two drinks on the night he was killed.
所以我才能讓你祖母達成和解
That was the reason I was able to get your grandmother to settle.
一出電梯就看到大個子
It's not every day I get off the elevator
這可不是每天都能碰到
and find someone in my firm that makes me look short.
看來你見過新客戶了
So you've seen our newest client?
你指斯科特的新客戶
You mean Scottie's newest client.
邁克爾·菲爾普斯或許是她的客戶
Michael Phelps may be her client,
但我們也能拿到速比濤[泳衣廠商]
but we're gonna get Speedo.
我為什么要因此改變主意呢
And why should that make me change my mind?
因為他們給的報酬比讓她的入股費更高
Because their fee is worth more than her buy-in.
你還認為這只是錢的問題
You still think this is about money.
我已經告訴過斯科特  現在我再告訴你
I told this to Scottie, and now I'm going to tell it to you.
我們的人事變動太多了
We've had too much turnover.
不能再變了
We can't have any more.
杰西卡  我告訴你  她入伙了
Jessica, I'm telling you she's in.
那她就更不用擔心
Then she shouldn't have any problem
把錢放入自己公司里了
putting her money where her mouth is.
不是這樣的
It's not right.
哈維  我們該談談這件事了
Harvey, it's time you and I had the talk.
我知道孩子是怎么來的
I know where babies come from.
可你知道情侶間要如何相處嗎
But do you know how couples stay together?
你想說什么
What are you getting at?
丹尼爾和我接管這間律所的時候
When Daniel and I took over the firm,
我們推心置腹地談過了
We had a heart-to-heart.
他有個理念我十分贊同
He had a philosophy that I agreed to live by.
丹尼爾就是坨狗屎
Daniel was a piece of shit.
那不代表他的理念也是
Doesn't mean his philosophy was.
洗耳恭聽
I'm listening.
他告訴我  要維持合伙人關系
He told me, for a partnership to work,
一把手和二把手之間必須有信任
there has to be trust between number one and number two.
你不一定要贊同我
You don't have to agree with me,
但你必須相信  我會聽你的意見
but you have to trust that I listen to you,
我的決定是合理的
that my decisions are reasoned,
以及我會做我認為對的事
and that I am doing what I think is right.
杰西卡
Jessica--
公司不能有兩個老大
You can't have two presidents, Harvey.
現在我選擇相信你說的
Now I chose to trust you when you said
你不想成為經營合伙人
you didn't want to be managing partner.
-那是真的嗎  -是
- Was that true or not? - It was.
那你就得接受這個
Then I need you to accept this.
如果我有個主意
What if I had an idea
能讓我們都得償所愿呢
where maybe we can both get what we want?
洗耳恭聽
I'm listening.
我從來沒這樣過
That's never happened to me before.
-沒事的  -不  有事
- It's okay. - No, it isn't.
《黑鷹墜落》
Black Hawk Down.
首先
First of all,
那部電影很棒  你該感到驕傲
that's an amazing movie, and you should be proud
能用它來雙關
that you are associated with it.
其次  我想我知道問題所在
And second of all, I think I know what the problem is.
真的嗎
You do?
是因為檔案室里發生的事
It's about what happened in the file room.
聽著  希拉  我都說不出
Listen, sheila, I can't tell you
那件事有多讓我苦惱
how that's been weighing on my mind.
不  我明白
No, I get it.
現在我們已經正式戀愛了
Now that we've declared our love,
你認為我是個好女孩
you think of me as a good girl.
但你希望我是個壞女孩
And you need me to be bad.
-什么  -這很正常
- What? - It happens all the time.
我們現在確定關系了  你覺得
We're in a relationship now, and you think that changes
這會改變我們性關系的本質
the nature of our sexual relationship.
但我向你保證
But I am here to assure you...
我可以很壞的
I can be bad.
-好吧  其實這不是我…  -騙人
- Okay, that's not actually what-- - Liar.
冷靜點
Take it easy.
我是說認真的
I am being serious right now.
你覺得我不是認真的
You think I'm not being serious?
我認真的要命
I'm deadly serious.
再叫一遍
Say it again.
你知道嗎
Well, what do you know?
《黑暗騎士崛起》
The Dark Knight Rises.
-她同意了  -是嗎
- She went for it. - She did?
只是有個條件
One catch.
什么
What?
你得簽一份萬無一失的非競爭條款
You have to sign an ironclad noncompete.
如果你離開  你就不能代理
You can't represent any Pearson Specter clients
皮爾遜-斯佩克特的任何客戶
if you leave.
-包括菲爾普斯  -包括菲爾普斯
- Including Phelps? - Including Phelps.
那和之前說的讓我付錢入伙有什么區別
How is that any different than paying in early?
-有五十萬的區別  -哈維
- It's $1/2 million different. - Harvey.
斯科特  這已經是最好的條件了
Scottie, this is the best we're gonna do.
菲爾普斯是個財神
Phelps brings in the money.
但如果你離開了還把他帶走了
But if you leave and take him away,
這對杰西卡有什么好處呢
What good does that do Jessica?
杰西卡還是你
Jessica or you?
你在說笑嗎  你在質疑我嗎
Are you kidding? Are you questioning me?
你之前就總是操縱整個局勢
You've been known to manipulate situations before.
要是我說了算  我就直接讓你入伙了
If it were up to me, I'd waive your whole buy-in.
現在我知道了你就是個人渣
Now I know you're full of shit.
沒錯  我是
You're right, I am.
準備好支票  六個月后  你就得付錢了
So get your check ready, 'cause in six months, you're paying it.
我們真要這么做嗎
Are we really doing this?
簽了它  交給杰西卡
Sign it. Give it to Jessica.
明天我們就在我家吃晚飯慶祝
Tomorrow we'll celebrate with dinner at my place.
你從哪弄來的
Where did you get this?
里納爾迪
Rinaldi.
邁克  我知道你在想什么
Mike, I know what you're thinking,
但法律上來說你父親沒有喝醉
But your father wasn't legally drunk.
是  但他也不是完全清醒
Yeah, but he wasn't sober either.
而且我怎么知道那兩瓶酒
And how do I know those two drinks aren't
是不是剛好就是他...
the split second that he needed not to...
你并不知道那和這次事故
You don't know that this had
有沒有關系
anything to do with the accident.
瑞秋  你知不知道我有多希望
Rachel, do you have any idea how many times I have wished
那晚他們沒有出門
that they hadn't gone out that night
或者他選了別的路線回家
or that they had taken a different route home
或者其他上千種可能
or any one of a thousand other things,
但只有一件  只有一件是我沒想過的
but the one thing--the one thing that I never wished
就是我父親被醉鬼撞死的那晚
is that my father hadn't been drinking
沒喝酒就好了
the night that he got killed by a drunk--
我知道他不是完人
I know he wasn't perfect.
但他曾經是
But he was.
他對我來說是完美的
He was perfect to me, and...
而我不想懷疑
I don't want to have to wonder
這是否全是他的錯
if this is all his fault.
邁克
Mike.
他就是想讓你這樣
He is just trying to get to you.
那他成功了
Well, he's got to me.
我是說  我和他又有什么差別呢  瑞秋
I mean, how am I any different than him, Rachel?
因為這是一起扯淡的訴訟
Because it's a bullshit claim.
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道我會贏
I know I'm gonna win.
但我不知道該不該
But I don't know.
你在這啊
Here you are.
-我到處找你來著  -怎么了
- Been looking all over for you. - Why?
我只是想為我侵犯你
I just wanted to apologize once again
電腦里的隱私再次道歉
for crossing the threshold of your electronic area.
沒關系  路易
It's okay, Louis.
不  不  我入侵了你的計算機
No, no, I breached your mainframe.
我愧對你
No excuse.
你的臉怎么這么紅
Why is your face so red?
因為你給了我一個世上最棒的建議
It's because you gave me the greatest advice in the world.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
總之我永遠不會告訴希拉
Let's just say that I'm never gonna tell sheila what I did
那晚我在檔案室的事  永遠不
in that file room that night, ever.
那我接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
現在失陪一下
Now if you'll excuse me,
我得往臉上糊點豌豆消腫
I need to put some peas on my face.
你那招沒用  我并沒因此退縮
Your move didn't work. I didn't go into a tailspin.
我沒打算讓你退縮
I wasn't trying to send you into a tailspin.
我只是想讓你了解真相
I was just trying to get you to understand.
我現在了解了
Well, I do understand.
但那不代表我會出賣我的客戶
That doesn't mean I'm gonna sell my client out.
那你是來干嘛的
Then why are we here?
你要起訴  應該起訴這些人
You want to sue someone, you should sue these people.
支架上的藥物涂層
They're the ones that make the medicine
就是他們制作的
that stent was coated with.
你知道這些藥物和這個案子有關嗎
And you know that medicine has something to do with this case?
我知道足夠多的不利于他們的證據
I know there's as much evidence against them
和不利我客戶的證據一樣多
as there is against my client.
你告訴我這些
That's why you're pointing me there,
就因為他們不是你的客戶
because they're not your client.
福爾曼先生不會起死回生
You know, nothing's gonna bring Mr. Foreman back.
就像我的父母
Just like there's nothing
也不會回來了
that's gonna bring my parents back.
這是我能想到讓你客戶得到償金最好的辦法
This is the best way I can see to get your client compensation.
如果你以為你做了正確的事  那你錯了
If you think you're doing the right thing, you're wrong.
我只是想幫忙
I'm trying to help,
但我不會出賣我的客戶
but I'm not gonna sell my client out.
這只是個折衷的辦法
It's a half measure.
好吧  還有另一個辦法
All right, then here's the other half.
我指出的你的致命弱點
I pointed out your Achilles' heel
就是那張照片  我在臉書上找到的
when I found that photo, and I found it on Facebook.
幫你客戶個忙  讓他們在你提交訴訟前
Do your client a favor, and have them take it down
把照片刪掉吧
before you file that suit.
所以你要飛回倫敦  安排好你的生活
So you're gonna fly back to London, get your life in order,
兩周內搬回來
and move back in two weeks.
票已經定好了
Tickets are booked.
敬嶄新的合伙關系
Here's to your new partnership.
我只有一個問題
I just have one question.
為什么杰西卡會明確答應我
Why did Jessica specifically make me agree to something
只有你合同里有的條款
that's a standard part of your contracts?
你查我
You checked up on me.
我沒有查你  我只是深入了解了一下
I didn't check up on you. I'm thorough.
有區別嗎
What's the difference?
老天  哈維  別轉移話題
God damn it, Harvey, don't change the subject.
你做了什么
What did you do?
我替你付了買入股份款
I fronted your buy-in.
我就知道  你買下了我
I knew it. You bought me.
我不是買你  我是給我們倆時間
I didn't buy you, I bought us time.
這是律師的回答  這是扯淡
That is a lawyer's response, and it's bullshit.
你怎么能這么做
How could you do that?
斯科特  你的反應就像我殺了人一樣
Scottie, you're acting like I killed someone.
我沒殺人
I didn't.
你買下我  然后我就能和你睡覺
You paid so that I could sleep with you
同時還能留在這
and be here at the same time!
-你知道這給我什么感覺嗎  -覺得幸運嗎
- Do you know what that makes me? - Lucky?
-不好笑  -我沒搞笑
- That's not funny. - I didn't mean it to be.
我出錢是因為我希望你留下來
I paid because I want you to stay.
我把它當作浪漫之舉
I did it as a romantic gesture.
是啊  美女或許愛演浪漫電影
Yeah, well, pretty woman may have been a romantic movie,
但朱莉亞·羅伯茨還是個妓女
But Julia Roberts was still a hooker.
電影《美麗俏佳人》
又開始說電影了嗎
Now you come up with a movie reference?
哈維  你能想象我發現這件事后
Harvey, can you imagine how that makes me feel
是什么感受嗎
to find that out?
你到底想讓我說什么呢
Well, what do you want me to say, huh?
我不擅長做這種事
I'm not perfect at this,
你也不必把這當作浪漫
and you don't have to believe that was romantic,
但如果你愿意相信我的話是最好了
but it would be nice if you believed that I thought it was.
哈維  如果杰西卡不肯讓步
Harvey, it would have been romantic
而你求著我留下  那才是浪漫
if you had begged me to stay when Jessica wouldn't budge,
但這  這不是浪漫
but this, this is not romantic.
這是操控
This is manipulative.
你都打算去別的地方工作了
You were about to take a job somewhere else.
所以說你操控欲強
That's what makes it manipulative!
你是在說你從沒操控過我嗎
Are you telling me you've never been manipulative with me?
我回來后從沒有過
Not since I've been back.
我努力去克服
I had to learn the hard way,
但我恐怕你從沒努力過
and I'm afraid that you haven't learned that at all.
你是說我是個混蛋嗎
So you're saying I'm an asshole?
是啊  我就是這意思  你個混蛋
Yes, that is what I'm saying, that you are an asshole,
但我真正想說的是
but what I'm really saying
我們應該開始對彼此坦誠
is that we need to start being honest with each other.
-坦誠一切嗎  -一切
- About everything? - Everything.
你重做那份試卷
You know that paper you had to redo,
是因為甘恩教授說他沒有收到
because Professor Gunn said he never got it?
他真的沒收到
He never got it.
狗娘養的
Son of a bitch.
我怎么會知道
How was I supposed to know
你沒有存進硬盤里
you didn't save it to your hard drive?
因為我告訴過你
Because I told you that.
你知道你說話的時候  我從來不聽的
You know I don't listen when you say things.
你個混蛋
You are an asshole.
這樣就對了
This is good.
說實話就對了
Honesty is good.
我告訴麗貝卡·卡琳你是基佬
I told Rebecca Carlin you were gay.
但她還是跟我睡了
She slept with me anyway.
只睡了一次
Once.
對啊
Yeah.
她為什么只跟我睡一次呢
Why did she only sleep with me once?
因為我還告訴她你有梅毒
Because I also told her that you had crabs.
真不地道
That's not cool.
這樣真好
This is good.
是啊
It is.
我是認真的  斯科特
I am in this, Scottie.
好吧
Okay.
我也是
So am I.
看看你的成績  邁克爾·詹姆斯·羅斯
Well, let's see what you got, Michael James Ross.
優等成績
Magna cum laude.
連咱們的聰明先生也無法獲得最優成績嗎
So mr. Smarty pants couldn't even manage summa cum laude?
是啊  我也沒得到  又能怎樣
Yeah, well, so what if I couldn't either?
什么  沒上過《法律評論》
What? No Law Review?
要么沒請你  要么你沒投稿
Well, either you weren't asked, or you didn't serve.
管他呢  我贏了
Either way, I win.
"A"
"A."
國際法"B+"
B-plus in International Law?
拜托  我閉著眼睛都拿了最高分
Oh, come on, I aced that class with my eyes closed.
合同法"A"  這才像話
"A" in Contracts. That's legit.
遺產規劃"A-"
A-minus in Estate Planning?
邁克要是在  可別忘了無囑而終
Remind me to not die intestate with Mike Ross around.
你要的卷尺
Tape measure, as requested.
看起來很興奮啊
You look really excited.
-今天好辛苦  -是啊
- Long day. - I know.
我們能不能先放下手頭的活
Is there any chance we can punt this,
去吃點東西
maybe go grab some dinner?
行啊  或者我們也可以想想
We could, or we could accept that moving in together
住在一起也許就意味著我們得不計前嫌
sometimes means we have to just shake off our crappy days
處理一些事情  比如商量一下家具
and deal with things like furniture negotiations.
是啊  這聽上去
Yeah, that doesn't sound
我是不可能接受的啊
like anything I want to accept at all.
那慘了
Too bad.
這是你的命了
This is your life now.
瑞秋  聽我說  我想
Rachel, look, I'm trying...
你說你爸爸喜歡慶祝一些小事情
You said that your dad liked to celebrate the little things,
我想也許我們也該開始那么做
and I thought maybe we should start doing that too.
比如商量家具嗎
You mean like furniture negotiations?
我是說我們的初次約會
I mean our first date.
看來我什么也別想吃了
So does that mean I'm not gonna be able to eat anything?
因為那晚菜單上的東西我都不喜歡
'cause I didn't like anything on the menu that night.
那不是我們的初次約會
That wasn't our first date.
我們初次約會是在法律圖書室
Our first date was in the law library.
-壽司  -壽司
- Sushi. - Sushi.
那是我的第一個案子
That was my first case.
我知道
I know.
你那時太嫩了
Oh, you were so green.
哈維跑進來讓咱們別在桌底下調情
Harvey came in and told us to stop playing footsie.
我還記得
Oh, I remember that.
我那時可不止想跟你在桌底下調情
I wanted to do a lot more than play footsie with you.
我知道
I know.
我看到你看了我五次
I caught you staring at me five times.
那看來還有好多次你沒看到
Oh, so I guess you didn't catch all the other times then.
我看到了  只是想放你一馬
I did, just trying to let you off the hook.
瑞秋
Rachel...
這太完美了
This is perfect.
還沒呢
Not yet.
現在才完美
Now it is.
椅子在哪里
So where's the chair?
不行
No.
您找我
You wanted to see me?
你有沒有上吉拉德教授的法律職業道德課
Professor Gerard's legal ethics class--you take it?
當然有了  每個人都得上的
Of course, everyone had to take it.
你得了多少分
What'd you get?
輕松拿下  我拿了個"A-"
Killed it. I got an a-minus.
不奇怪
Out of curiosity,
你聽說過誰得了"A+"嗎
did you ever hear of anybody ever getting an a-plus?
什么  沒有
What? No.
他就是以給分不超過"A"出名的
He's famous for never giving higher than an "A."
他不搞這套
He doesn't believe in it.
謝謝  薩蒙  沒事了
Thank you, Simon. That'll be all.